Where's the sodium go?
Well, they'll be like a sodium.
They'll want to hang
out close by these.
There will be these
ions in there.
These sodium ions will
be in there still, right?
If it was Na2O, if
it's something else
and it's a different kind of
ion that might be leftover,
but the main thing is I've
delivered the chemistry
needed to cut this.
And this is called
chain scission.
There's a term for it, chain
scission, the technical term
for cutting glass pasta.
Well, this is powerful.
This is very powerful
because if I can cut this--
those are the silicate
groups, right?
And if I can cut them, then I
can change another property.
Look, I can change
the viscosity.
I've hit another one of those
three reasons why glass forms.
And so I'll show you a
slide in a minute that
shows you the change
in the viscosity,
but just to give you a
sense of what can happen,
how does that impact?
How does that impact?
Well, for silica crystal,
the melting point
is greater than 1,200 C. For Tg
of soda-lime glass, it's 500 C.